Guide to the Americas collection, 1811-1920 MS 518
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
- Series II: Central America, 1821-1829,1861-1920; 242464
  - Subseries: Guatemala, 1821-1829, 242469
    - Sub-subseries I: 1822-1829. Collection of printed materials documenting the tribulations of the early years of nation-building following independence from Spain. Guatemala and Xilotepque. In Spanish. (Arc, #5), 242470
      - Item 30. 1826 Santa Maria, Jose Andres de. Guatemala: Impr. De la Union Frente de Santa Rosa, 1826. Pamphlet. Preservativo contra el impio é irreligioso folleto. Aviso oportuno a las autoridades y al Pueblo... 8vo. Church-State controversy and attacks on the Church. Santa Maria defends the Church-State relationship and the faith. Modern wrappers. 41 pp., 242484 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - Item 31. 1827 [Montalvo, C. Maria]. Guatemala: por Beteta, 1827. Pamphlet. Dictamen de una commission del consejo representative del Estado del Salvador en la acusacion, interpuesta por el C. José Maria Montalvo contra el C. Jose Ignacio de Maricorena… Accusing Marticorena, Secretary General of the government, of malfeasance of office. Modern wrappers. A few stains of mildew of water. 3 pp., 242483 (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - Item 32. 1828 [Valete]. Guatemala: Impr. Mayor, Casa de Porras, 1828. 8 vo. Glosa respondona al voto, o discurso que en el año de 1823 se inserto en el papel llamado Alcance al número 5 de la Tribuna… Urging censorship and restriction on importing foreign books and newspapers. A point by point refutation of an 1823 article. Modern wrappers. 27 pp., 242482 (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - Item 33. 1828. Aycinena, Mariano. Guatemala: Impr. Mayor, 1828. Pamphlet. Manifiesto del gefe del estado a los pueblos. Folio. 8 pp., 242481 (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - Item 34. [Guatemala]. [Guatemala, 5-28-1829] Broadside. [drop-title] Por la Intenndencia de temporalidades se ha anunciado al publico que se van á dar en arrendamiento todas las fincas que pertenecian á los Conventos extinguidos… Oblong quarto. 1pg., 242480 (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - Item 35. [Dardon, Marcos]. [Guatemala, 4-30-1829]. Broadside. La Asamblea Lejislativa del estado de Guatemala à sus comiténtes. [Begins:] Despues de tantas victimas y de tan dolorosos sacrificios, ocasionados por los tiranos usurpadores de la soberania del estado, la representacion restituida ya à sus funciones, os convoca hoi para elejir vuestros funcionarios. Folio. 2 pp., 242479 (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - Item 36. [Guatemala] [Guatemala, 1829]. Broadside. Elecciones de Quesaltenango, y Totonicapam. Small quarto. 1p., 242478 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      - Item 37. [Guatemala] [Guatemala, 5-27-1829] Broadside. Tabla en que se demuestra el escrutinio y regulacion de votos de todos las juntas departmentales para magistrados suplentes de la Corte Superior de Justicia. Folio (folding). 1 p., 242477 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      - Item 38. Rodriguez. [Guatemala, 7-24-1829] Broadside. …Órden N. 253 [Begins:] Sancionado por el Consejo reprentativo, ha recibido el Gobierno del Estado, la órden que signe [sic]. La Asamblea tomando en consideracion las solicitu.des de algunos sexagenarios, excluidos del decreto de amnistía, dado en 4 de junio último. Small 8vo. 1p., 242476 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      - Item 39. Rodrigues, Juan Manuel. [Guatemala, 6-24-1829]. Broadsheet. … Órden N. 253. [Begins:] Los ciudadanos diputados secretaries de la Asambléa lejislativa del Estado, me han dirijido en esta fecha la órden que sigue: La Asamblea tomando en consideracion las solicitudes de algunos secsagenarios [sic] escluidos del decreto de amnistia dado en 4 de junio último. Small 8vo. 2pp, 242475 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      - Item 40. Galvez, Mariano. [Guatemala, 5-5-1829] Broadsheet. [drop-title] Con fecha de 29 de febrero de este año el gobierno se sirvió expedir el decreto siguente… Decreto. Considerando que las municipalidades actuales no han sido nombradas con la libertad necesaria pues que se eligieron sus individuos bajo una fuerza opresora, he tenido a bien decretar; 1. Que se convoque al pueblo de esta Ciudad por medio del bando de estilo para que en el proximo Domingo se celebren las elecciones primarias, y el primer dia festivo inmediato se elijan los alcaldes regidores y sindico. Small 8vo. 2 pp., 242474 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      - Item 41. Rodriguez. [Guatemala, 8-1-1829] Broadside. Órden N. I. [Begins:] Los CC. Diputados Secretarios de la Asambléa legislative del Estado, me han dirigido con esta fecha la órden que sigue: ,, [sic] En este dia se han constituido y formado en Segunda legislature ordinaria del Estado, con arreglo à las leyes de la material, los representantes nuevamente electos, y prestado el correspondiente juramento; acordando abrir sus sesiones ordinarias el jueves seis del corriente. Small 8vo. 1p., 242473 (Box 2, Folder 15)
      - Item 42. 1829. Espinosa, Nicholas. Guatemala: Imp. De la Union, [4-26-1829] Pamphlet. La Asamblea restaurada a los pueblos del Estado de Guatemala. [Begins:] Ha llegado por finconciudadanos, el termino feliz de nuestros sufrimientos. Folio. 5 pp., 242472 (Box 2, Folder 15)
      - Item 43. 1829. [Guatemala] Guatemala: Impr. Nueva, 1829. Pamphlet. Boletin. Top of first leaf torn and missing, affecting text. Attempted preservation. No. 17 (pp. 105-12)., 242471 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Subseries: Panama Canal, 1861-1920, 242465
    - 01-23-1861. Letter: Hoadley, David. As president of the Panama Rail Road Company re the transcontinental railroad. New York. To Senator W. Fessenden. 5 pp. On "Office Panama Rail Road Company" letterhead. (ALS, #32), 242468 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Isthmian Canal Commission correspondence and documents, 1906-1920., 242467 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - 12 color prints of Canal scenes. (#36.02), 242466 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Series III: Mexico, 1821-1865; 242457
  - 2-4-1821. Iturbide, Agustin. Plan del Señor Coronel D. Agustin Iturbide. Copia del Suplemento al número 14 de la Abeja poblana. Mexico: Oficina de D. J. M. Benavente y Socios. The first Mexico City printing of the Plan of Iguala. 2 pp. (Br, #1), 242463 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - [1835] Rayon, Ramon. El Ciudadano Ramon Rayon, General de Brigada Y Gobernador Del Distrito Federal. [Mexico]. Initialed in manuscript by Governor Rayon. Describing the national debt of the Mexican states and declaring that Sonora (of which Arizona is still a part) and Sinaloa are responsible for payment of at least twenty percent of that debt. (Br, #12) (oversize), 242462 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - [2-19-1847] Cuartel General del Egercito. #20. Notifies the Mexican people of the dictates of martial law under U.S. occupation, naming in 12 separate directives the crimes which are punishable under U.S. law. By order of the "Mayor General" (Weinfield Scott) signed in type, "N.L. Scott" (Br, #38), 242461 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - [1852] [Hargous, Peter A.] "Remonstrance. The Memorialist, citizens of the United States…" Protesting Mexico's repudiation of the Memorialists' franchises and land transfers, which endangered their project to construct the Tehuantepec Railroad across the Isthmus. 36 pp. (Pm, #56), 242460 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - 11-15-1865 Letter: Price, Sterling. Writing from the newly formed colony of Cordova, Mexico, describing the nearly idyllic conditions which he has found. To Col. Thomas L. Snead. 4 pp. (ALS, #9), 242459 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Map of Battle of El Molino del Rey (Map shows deployment of United States forces throughout the Battle of El Molino del Rey, which took place on September 8th, 1847), 1850; 242458 (Drawer # 4)
- Series IV: United States, 1823-1893; 242356
  - Subseries: General, 1851-1893, 242452
    - 5-18-1847. Tyler, John. Letter: "When the Mexican gulph [sic] shall be crowded with innumerable ships freighted with the rich production of Texas both Coastwide and outward - meeting other ships loaded with the frieghts of all the world to give in exchange - then will it be seen that my labors were not in vain to advance the highest destinies of the country...". To Robert Tyler Esq. 3 pp. Plus address leaf. (# 65), 242456 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - [2-13-1861] Vance, Zebulon. To the citizens of the eighth Congressional district of North Carolina. Explaining that the Cotton States have "gladly seized upon the election of Lincoln as the occasion, rather than the cause for breaking up the Union"; they have labored "for disunion for thrity years, inflamed with magnificent and visionary conceptions of a great Southern Republic… to conquer and annex all the countries seated in the basin of the Gulf of Mexico" and Cuba as well. 7 pp. (Pm, # 54), 242455 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - 02-12-1898 Sigsbee, Charles. Ordering supplies for his ship, the USS Maine, [three days before it was destroyed in an explosion]. Havana, Cuba. Also signed by Lt. Richard Wainwright, Commander of the USN. 1 p. (DS, #34), 242454 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - 03-18-1893. Letter: Marti, Jose. Seeking financial support for El Tara, a revolutionary newspaper printed in Key West for distribution in Cuba. To the presidents of Cuban exiled clubs in Florida. 4 pp. (ALS, #33), 242453 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Subseries: Texas (modern boundaries), 1823-1860, 242357
    - [5-5-1823] [Texas currency] Very early currency for Austin's colony and Mexico. Due to a severe paper shortage, the currency was printed on the reverse of an out-dated papal bull., 242451 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Sub-series I: 1825-1835. Eighteen manuscript documents relating to official and military matters in Goliad, Bexar (current day Texas)., 242432
      - Item 1: Jose Maria Valdez. ALS. Goliad, Bejar. 2-14-1825. Ordering that a resident of Goliad be brought before Valdez' court on two charges of horse theft. To José Maria Zambano. 2 pp., 242450 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - Item 2: J.G. de Torde. ALS. Goliad. 5-23-183[0]. Sustaining a widow's claim of title to her deceased husband's lands, and suspending additional claims until the Supreme Government of the State reviews the matter. To C. Antonio Vasquez. 2 pp. [incomplete], 242449 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - Item 3: Ramon Musquiz. ALS. Goliad, Bejar. 3-23-1831. Reiterating a decree issued by the Vice-President of the United Mexican States allocating up to 20,000 pesos for the "urgent work" needed on the Huehetoca Channel. 3 pp., 242448 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - Item 4: Ramon Musquiz. ALS. Goliad, Bejar. 3-8-1831. Concerning the town's budget, tax revenues and extraordinary expenses. 2 pp., 242447 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - Item 5: Jose Maria Folcon. ALS. Goliad. 3-23-1831. Asking for various reforms to be enacted. 1p., 242446 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - Item 6: Ramon Musquiz. ALS. Goliad, Bejar. 9-19-1831. Decree of the Governor of the State. 3 pp., 242445 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - Item 7: Ramon Musquiz. ALS. Goliad, Bejar. 12-9-1831. Acknowledging receipt of correspondence. 3 pp., 242444 (Box 3, Folder 12)
      - Item 8: Aristiaga. ALS. Goliad, Bejar. 7-27-1833. Transmitting a communication from the Supreme Government of the State praising recent actions taken to sustain a local garrison: "…because of those measures the public peace was never threatened, nor was your authority, and neither did the honorable citizenry take part in some revolutionary movements that can and must be considered the worst of criminal acts." 3 pp., 242443 (Box 3, Folder 12)
      - Item 9: [Goliad] AN. Bejar. [1835]. 1p., 242442 (Box 3, Folder 12)
      - Item 10: Angel Navarro. ALS. Goliad, Bejar. 2-11-1835. Transmitting an authorized copy of the act for the election of an authorized Representative and substitute at the State Congress. 1 p., 242441 (Box 3, Folder 12)
      - Item 11: Juan Elizondo. ALS. Matamoros. 3-23-1835. Requesting assistance in locating Mr. Francisco Cardenas, who has been summoned to answer the divorce proceedings initiated by his wife. To Juan Flor Eretuano. 3 pp., 242440 (Box 3, Folder 12)
      - Item 12: [Goliad]. L. Goliad. 2-13-1835. Approving the establishment of a corporation and allowing its representatives to begin conducting business in the city. 2 pp., 242439 (Box 3, Folder 12)
      - Item 13: Angel Navarro. ALS. Goliad, Bejar. 2-12-1835. Defending the land claim of a widow, and condemning the "scandalous attempt" to disposses her of her lands. To J. Maria Valdes. 2 pp., 242438 (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - Item 14: Jose Antonio Delahoz et al. ALS. Goliad. 4-18-1835, 4-23-1835, & 4-25-1835. Three separate letters written on a single leaf of paper. One side contains two separate statements concerning city government and court expenses. On the reverse is a plea for leniency on behalf of Jose Antonio Delahoz, a soldier who escaped from Goliad Prison, and took refuge in the Parish Church. Asks the authorities to keep in mind that "he was seeking divine protection and for that reason… [begs and asks] for lenience in the sentence, and gentleness in law that judges him." 2 pp., 242437 (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - Item 15: Antonio Jose Guadaloupe Santos. ALS. Goliad. 5-4-1835; 5-6-1835. Two separate statements written on a single leaf of paper. The first relates to tonnage-duties and income earned from the principal. The second concerns the purchase of "500 shot-filled cartridges" for the Civic Militia. 1 p., 242436 (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - Item 16: [Goliad]. AD. Goliad. 5-8-1835. Tabular record of the arms and saddlery taken by each individual on an expedition marching to the Capital of Monclova. 2 pp., 242435 (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - Item 17: [Goliad]. AD. [Goliad]. [5-8-1835].Computation of the equipment carried by each man in RCC 14.17. 2 pp., 242434 (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - Item 18: Angel Navarro. ALS. 7-29-1835. Goliad, Bejar. Transmitting a communication from the Supreme Government of the State, re. the appointment of Jose de Jesus Grande to Inspector of Maritime Customs for Matagorda. 2 pp., 242433 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Subseries II: 1836-1860. Collection of approximately 75 U.S. Government imprints, consisting of state resolutions for an against the contemplated U.S. annexation of Texas; resolutions of the State of Texas; and documents about Texas. Subjects included annexation, slavery, Santa Fe expedition, boundary with New Mexico, Compromise of 1850, Mexico, adjustment of matters involving the Republic of Texas, and other significant topics., 242358
      - Item 52.02 1837 [Howard, Benjamin C.] Printed document. Independence of Texas. Mr. Howard, from the Committee on Foreign Affiars, to which the subject had been referred, made the following Report: The Committee on Foreign Affiars, to which the President's message and sundry memorials in relation to Texas were referred… 24th Cong. 2d Sess. HR240. [Washington:] Blair & Rives. [2-18-1837] 1 p., 242431 (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - Item 52.03 1837 Van Buren, Martin. Printed Document. Annexation of Texas and Boundary with Mexico. Message from the President of the United States, in compliance with a resolution of the House of Representatives of the 13th instant, respecting an Annexation of Texas to the United States. 25th Cong., 1st Sess. D40 & 42. [Washington:] Thomas Allen. [10-10-1837] Includes correspondence by John Forsyth, et al. First few pages foxing. 94 pp., 242430 (Box 3, Folder 15)
      - Item 52.04 1838. [Rhode Island]. Bowen, Henry. Printed Document. Resolutions of the Legislature of Rhode Island, Against the annexation of Texas to the United States. 25th Cong., 2d Sess. SD281. [Washington:] Blair &Rives. [4-17-1838] 2 pp., 242429 (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - Item 52.05 1838 [Ohio]. Vance, Joseph. Printed Document. Resolutions of the General Assembly of Ohio, protesting the annexation of Texas to the United States. 25th Cong., 2d Sess. SD281. [Washington:] Blair & Rives. [3-8-1838] 2 pp., 242428 (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - Item 52.06 1838 [Tennessee]. Cocke, John. Printed Document. Resolutions of the General Assembly of Tennessee, in favor of the annexation of Texas to the United States. 25th Cong., 2d Sess. SD384. [Washington:] Blair & Rives. [4-17-1838]. 2 pp., 242427 (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - Item 52.07 1840. Woodbury, Levi. Printed Document. Inland Trade with Mexico. Letter from the Secretary of the Treasurer, in compliance with a resolution of the House of Representatives of the United States, calling for information concerning inland trade with Mexico. 26th Cong, 1st Sess. HR191. [Washington:] Blair & Rives. [4-17-1840]. Uncut leaves. 8 pp., 242426 (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - Item 52.08 1841. Tyler, John. Printed Document. Relations with Texas. Message from the President of the United States, transmitting a report of the Secretary of State, touching the relations between the United States and the Government of Texas. 27th Cong., 2d Sess. HR12. [12-13-1841]. Includes correspondence by Daniel Webster. 2 pp., 242425 (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - Item 52.09 1842. [Alabama]. Terry, Nathaniel. Printed Document. Resolutions of the General Assembly of Alabama, in favor of the admission of Texas into the Union. 27th Cong., 2d Sess. SD55. [1-21-1842]. 1 p., 242424 (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - Item 52.10 1842. [Mississippi]. Roberts, Robert W. Printed Document. Resolutions of the Legislature of Mississippi, in favor of the annexation of Texas to the United States. 27th Cong., 2d Sess. SD277. [Washington:] Thomas Allen. [4-29-1842]. 1 p., 242423 (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - Item 52.11 1842. Tyler, John. Printed Document. Message from the President of the United States, communicating, in compliance with a resolution of the Senate, information touching the proceedings under the Convention of the 11th April, 1839, between the United States and the Mexican Republic. 27th Cong., 2d Sess. SD320 [Washington:] Thomas Allen. [6-14-1842]. Includes correspondence by Daniel Webster, John Forsyth, et al. 255 pp. + 12 folding tables., 242422 (Box 3, Folder 17)
      - Item 52.12 1842. Tyler, John. Printed Document. Message from the President of the United States, communicating, in compliance with a resolution of the Senate, copies of correspondence with the Government of Mexico. 27th Cong., 2d Sess. SD325 [6-16-1842]. Includes correspondence by Daniel Webster, et al. 104 pp., 242421 (Box 3, Folder 18)
      - Item 52.13 1844. [Merchants of NY]. Brower, J.H. Printed Document. Memorial of a Number of Merchants and Traders, Citizens of New York, praying the ratification of a treaty of commerce and navigation between the United States and the Republic of Texas. 28th Cong., 1st Sess. SD 130. [2-22-1844]. 4 pp., 242420 (Box 3, Folder 19)
      - Item 52.14 1844. [Vermont]. Clarke, De Witt C. Printed Document. Resolutions Passed by the Legislature of the State of Vermont, against the annexation of Texas to the Union. 28th Cong., 1st Sess. SD166. [3-6-1844]. 1 p., 242419 (Box 3, Folder 19)
      - Item 52.15 1844. [Connecticut]. Printed Document. Memorial of a Number of Citizens of Connecticut, praying the ratification of a treaty of commerce and navigation between the United States and the Republic of Texas. 28th Congress, 1st Session. SD177. [3-11-1844]. 2 pp., 242418 (Box 3, Folder 19)
      - Item 52.16 1844. [New Jersey]. Printed Document. Memorial of a Number of Citizens of New Jersey, praying the ratification of a treaty of commerce and navigation between the United States and the Republic of Texas. 28th Cong. 1st Sess. SD219. [3-25-1844]. 1 p., 242417 (Box 3, Folder 20)
      - Item 52.17 1844. [Mississippi & Alabama]. Totten, James L. Printed Document. Resolutions of the Legislatures of Mississippi and Alabama, in favor of the annexation of Texas to the United States. 28th Cong., 1st Sess. SD215. [3-20-1844] 2 pp., 242416 (Box 3, Folder 20)
      - Item 52.18 1844. [Massachusetts] Walley, Samuel H. Printed Document. Resolutions of the General Assembly of Massachusetts, adverse to the annexation of Texas. 28th Cong., 1st Sess. SD219. [3-25-1844] 1 p., 242415 (Box 3, Folder 20)
      - Item 52.19 1844. [Prince George County, VA] Shands, William Jr. Printed Document. Texas. Proceedings of Citizens of Prince George County, Virginia, on the Subject of re-annexing Texas to the United States. 28th Cong., 1st Sess. HD259. [Washington:] Blair & Rives. [5-17-1844]. 2 pp., 242414 (Box 3, Folder 20)
      - Item 52.20 1844. [Darlington District, SC] Sims, A.D. Printed Document. Annexation of Texas. Resolutions in favor of the annexation of Texas, adopted at a primary meeting of the citizens of Darlington district, South Carolina. 28th Cong., 1st Sess. HD261. [Washington:] Blair & Rives. [5-29-1844] 2 pp., 242413 (Box 3, Folder 20)
      - Item 52.21 1844. Tyler, John. Printed Document. Message from the President of the United States, in answer to a resolution of the Senate of the 28th of May, 1844. 28th Cong., 1st Sess. SD351. [6-3-1844]. Includes correspondence by John C. Calhoun. 1 p., 242412 (Box 3, Folder 20)
      - Item 52.22 1844. Tyler, John. Printed Document. Message from the President of the United States, in answer to a resolution of the Senate of the 3d June, 1844. 28th Cong., 1st Sess. SD361. [6-4-1844]. Includes correspondence by John C. Calhoun. 1 p., 242411 (Box 3, Folder 20)
      - Item 52.23 1844. Tyler, John. Printed Document. Message from the President of the United States, communicating a letter from the minister of the United States at London, with reference to the treaty of annexation with Texas. 28th Cong., 1st Sess. SD367. [6-6-1844] Includes correspondence by Edward Everett. 2 pp., 242410 (Box 3, Folder 20)
      - Item 52.24 1844. [Connecticut]. Printed Document.Resolutions of the General Assembly of Connecticut, adverse to the annexation of Texas to the United States. 28th Cong., 1st Sess. SD402. [6-17-1844]. 1 p., 242409 (Box 3, Folder 20)
      - Item 52.25 1844. Tyler, John. Printed Document. Message from the President of the United States communicating (in compliance with a resolution of the Senate) copies of correspondence with the minister of the United States at France, in relation to the annexation of Texas to the United States. 28th Cong., 2d Sess. SD13. [12-23-1844]. Includes correspondence by John C. Calhoun. Leaves separated. 3 p., 242408 (Box 3, Folder 20)
      - Item 52.26 1845. [New Hampshire] Hibbard, Harry. Printed Document. Resolutions of the General Assembly of New Hampshire, in favor of the annexation of Texas, and of maintaining the rights of the United States over the Territory of Oregon. 28th Cong., 2d Sess. Sd22. [1-6-1845]. 2 pp., 242407 (Box 3, Folder 20)
      - Item 52.27 1845. Tyler, John. Printed Document. Message from the President of the United States, in reply to a resolution of the Senate of the 16th December, 1844, requesting information relative to the public debt and public lands of the Republic of Texas. 28th Congress, 2d. Sess. SD29. [1-7-1845]. Includes correspondence by John C. Calhoun, et al. 3 pp., 242406 (Box 3, Folder 21)
      - Item 52.28 1845. Tyler, John. Printed Document. Message from the President of the United States, in reply to a resolution of the Senate of the 19th December, 1844, requesting information in relation to various treaty stipulations between Texas and other independent Powers. 28th Cong., 2d Sess. SD30. [1-7-1845]. Includes correspondence by John C. Calhoun, et al. 11 pp. [Bound with:] The Committee on Military Affairs, to whom was referred the memorial of John Stockton, late a lieutenant in the United States Army, ask leave to submit the following report. 28th cong., 2d Sess., SD31. [1-8-1845]., 242405 (Box 3, Folder 21)